Jorge Romo

Senior Frontend Developer

romo.jorge126@gmail.com (440) 508-6823 412 Covington Ave, Odessa, TX 79763

Software developer with 6+ years of experience with a passion for both personal growth and web development. Detail-oriented, organized, and meticulous employee. Quick learner, strong reasoning, and problem-solving skills. Works at a fast pace to meet tight deadlines. Ready to apply my passion for coding to a talented engineering team to develop quality solutions.

SKILLS

JavaScript / Typescript (React, Angular, Node.js), SQL, NoSQL, GraphQL, RESTApis, Git, CI/CD, AWS

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Upwork Odessa, TX (Remote)

Freelance Software Developer

November 2024 - Present

- Demonstrated excellent communication and collaboration skills, working closely with clients to understand their needs and expectations, and providing regular updates and feedback.
- Showcased creativity and problem-solving abilities, using various WordPress features and plugins to create customized and responsive websites that met the clients' specifications and goals.

Skills: React.js, Angular, Node.js, WordPress, Javascript, Typescript, AWS, Git

Hitachi Vantara LLC - Hitachi Digital Service

Dallas, TX (Hybrid)

Sr. Frontend Engineer

March 2023 - November 2024

- Mentored 3+ new recruits, provided onboarding orientation seminars and conducted group and individual training sessions.
- Built a call center web app using Amazon Connect and Amazon QuickSight in collaboration with 3 teammates.
- Built and architected a library for rendering dynamic forms, enhancing development speed.
- Worked with the core team to develop a UI library containing atomic UI components and utilities, adhering to UX/UI design principles.

Skills: React.js, Angular, Node.js, Typescript, AWS, Git

Photon Interactive Private Limited

Dallas, TX (On-site)

Frontend Developer

September 2018 - March 2023

- Maintained site functionality with team updating pull requests and grooming program daily.
- Tasked with developing an automated scraper tool for extraction of data.
- Provided developers with an initialized codebase to speed up the development process.
- Produced UX/UI designs using React to production while working with the QA testing to improve program performance features.

Skills: React.js, Node.js, Javascript, Git

EDUCATION

University of North TexasBachelor of Science in Computer Science

Denton, TX
May 2018